# Derin K Joseph Software Engineer

✓ derinbino@gmail.com

**(**847)322-9793

www.derinjoseph.com

in Derin Joseph

Derin23

#### **PROFILE**

Experienced and self-motivated generalist engineer who specializes in building web applications. I started programming when I was 16 and I ended up making a career out of it. I am currently modernizing State Farm's auto insurance applications. I am always interested in learning new technologies and helping other people enter the field or progress in their careers. My goal is to become an engineering leader and help as many engineers as I can while exceeding expectations from my peers and leaders.

## **EDUCATION**

#### M.S in Information Technology: Software Development and Management, Liberty University

Coursework: Secure Software Engineering, Statistical Analysis & Data Mining, Database management, Software Development Management.

#### B.S in Information Technology: Web and Mobile Development, Liberty University

Coursework: Software development, Advanced Object-Oriented Programming, Networking, Database management, Internet architecture.

#### Associate of Applied Science: Web Development and Design, Dallas College

Coursework: Web Design Technology, Advance Program Concepts, Web Server Software, Web programming.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

04/2020 - present

## Software Engineer II, State Farm

- Used JSP and Angular for UI development.
- Utilized Spring Boot for building services and business logic.
- Unit tested all the code that was written using JUnit 5.
- Version controlled software using GitLab.
- Developed Restful APIs that communicate with the UI.
- Used Jenkins and Gitlab for DevOps.
- Pair programming and mob programming were utilized as needed.
- Took responsibility for finishing stories and meeting business requirements on time.
- Helped other members of the team to the best of my ability.

08/2019 - 03/2020

#### Software Engineer I, State Farm

- Used React and Ember for UI frameworks
- Developed backends for multiple applications using the Spring framework.
- Unit tested all the code that was written using JUnit 5.
- Version controlled software using GitLab.
- Helped develop Restful APIs that communicate with the UI.
- Learned and used a company-specific library for front-end development.
- Used a PostgreSQL database, passing data from UI to DB and the other way around.
- Took responsibility for finishing stories and meeting business requirements on time.

11/2018 - 07/2019

### Software Engineering Intern, Keep Dallas Beautiful

- Used HTML 5 and CSS for UI modifications.
- Developed Several templates to give the client choices.
- Once the template was chosen it was made into a functional prototype.
- I along with my team worked on transferring relevant data to the prototype
- Usability, UI, and Business Requirements were the main focus.
- Team collaboration and pair programming were a huge part of this project.
- Took a leadership role in given tasks and delivered everything on time



Backend

Java, Python, Spring, Springboot, REST, SOAP, GraphQL

Frontend

JavaScript, Typescript, React, Angular, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Databases

My SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Tools** 

Maven, Gradle, Jenkins, PCF, Gitlab